<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mark Laughery</title>
    <description>Designer and stuff</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 11:23:13 +0900</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 11:23:13 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I love design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Mark Laughery, and I’m a UX designer in Tokyo with four years of experience shipping mobile and virtual/augmented reality applications. Having spent most of my professional life in smaller product teams, I’ve had opportunities to sharpen my skills across every end of the UX spectrum. I enjoy all of it, but my path into design was by way of analytics and I’ve grown to recognize the importance of outcome-driven design and product strategy. IDEO’s “Talk less, do more” axiom and “build-to-think” methodology are core tenets to my approach, and I find my flow in the interaction design, prototyping, and research loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently work on Indeed’s employer product. Recent projects include a 2-year vision for the employer mobile app, a complete redesign of the messaging experience, and an internal tool for cross-team knowledge sharing. I work closely with product managers on strategy, user researchers on generative and evaluative research, content strategists on voice, and engineering to ensure quality input and output. I view trust as the central fulcrum to a productive team and seek to promote creativity from all corners of the office (and from users!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, having worked on teams in Seattle, New York, Austin, Nairobi, Saigon, and Tokyo, I recognize the importance of disparate views, cultures, and life experiences as ingredients to a truly user-centered product. Unless I’m making a grilled cheese, I try to avoid self-reference and love learning from smart folks around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/tpe1a1ykalymwhl/2019-resume.pdf?dl=0&quot;&gt;View resume&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/23/intro/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/10/23/intro/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Indeed</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My 2019 was spent in Tokyo leading the design of Indeed’s new employer messaging experience. It’s a big swing initiative to shift communication away from email and toward real-time chat as part of a wider effort to close the “black hole.” v1 shipped over the summer and is trending positively across all KPIs. 🤞&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a high-level overview of the genesis, early development, optimization, and vision for employer messaging. I do my best to supplement the story with relevant visuals and summarize my involvement at each step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/indeed/messaging/inboxOverview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;business-context&quot;&gt;Business context&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black hole (unresponsive employers) has been the biggest job seeker complaint since Indeed’s inception. Only 9.5% of job applications get a response.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have limited visibility into hiring outcomes. We failed to provide basic functionality and a centralized view of all conversations, which pushed 70% of employer communication out of the platform.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Employers using different Indeed products have a disjointed user experience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Templates are a critical part of their messaging workflow and we lacked proper management tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;design-challenges&quot;&gt;Design challenges&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make messaging feel lighter and faster by challenging email as the status quo for hiring communication.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Balance requirements from over eight teams around the world.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide sufficient marginal value over email to bring messaging activity back into the platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;project-details&quot;&gt;Project details&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Role:&lt;/strong&gt; UX lead&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team:&lt;/strong&gt; 2 designers, 1 design technologist, 1 user researcher. Extended team includes 7 developers, 1 PM, and 2 QA. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Output:&lt;/strong&gt; Messaging application on mobile and desktop. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights:&lt;/strong&gt; Working with a brilliant product manager and engineers. Presenting to SLT &amp;amp; 100+ designers across the org. Creating demo that SVP of Product presented at major HR conference. Shipped sweeping redesign of core employer experience that positively impacts tens of millions of people worldwide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;before--after&quot;&gt;Before &amp;amp; after&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/indeed/messaging/beforeAfter.png&quot; alt=&quot;Before and after&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyDiv&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;smll&quot;&gt;Phase 1&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt; Foundational user research &amp;amp; synthesis&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    Following a 40+ person sprint, we had a full team of engineers in the wings and very little user research to inform our initial product roadmap. As a result, a researcher and I launched a campaign to collect qualitative knowledge every week for two months. Our research included:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Synthesis of past research and experimentation in employer communication&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Digging into interaction logs to get baseline understanding of user behavior (e.g. conversation/message length, message contents, response times)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;On-site interviews with users&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Show-me sessions with existing messaging&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;In-app surveys&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Rapid prototyping and moderated usability testing&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;h5&gt;Key flows&lt;/h5&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A key output from this phase were three abstracted flows that aligned job seeker and employer vision&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/indeed/messaging/keyflows.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;My contribution:&lt;/strong&gt; Collected and summarized past research. Battled with SQL to get behavioral insight. Attended on-sites and observed show-me sessions. Designed in-app survey.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Maintained high-contact between cross-team stakeholders, design technologist, researcher, PM, and other designers to report out findings and share designs.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Partnered with product management to shape OKRs and MVP specification based on research, technical constraints, and company objectives.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;smll&quot;&gt;Phase 2&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;weekly-design-prototyping--usability-research-sprints&quot;&gt;Weekly design, prototyping &amp;amp; usability research sprints&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A typical UX has a healthy buffer between design, prototype development, and research. Given our aggressive timeline (we were simultaneously researching and building features for the first couple months 😬), our transition from foundational user research to prototyping and evaluation was abrupt. We were forced to bundle design and prototyping into one exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I partnered with a design technologist and researcher to generate a high fidelity prototype that was used for stakeholder communication and weekly sessions at the usability lab. Within 7-day sprints, we summarized research findings, adjusted designs, iterated  with product stakeholders, communicated changes to developers, revised the prototype, and created research plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My contribution:&lt;/strong&gt; Grand liason. Observed all research sessions and iterated mobile and desktop designs based on observations and internal product feedback. Produced extensive behavioral specifications to accompany prototype that shared referenced with developer team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/indeed/messaging/uxLab.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;The battleground, aka UX lab&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyDiv&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;smll&quot;&gt;Phase 3&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Ongoing optimization &amp;amp; experimentation&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Following launch and stabilization, I spent lunches sitting in a room with my PM watching session recordings (actual users in prod), and categorizing feedback from our monthly pulse survey. We took observed issues back to the team to find solutions. After quick brainstorming sessions, winning concepts were pulled into the research prototype and gut-checked on usertesting.com. This improvement process was powerful in ensuring seamless UX and effectively reduced CS tickets.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h5&gt;Hotjar recording + categorized feedback from our monthly pulse survey&lt;/h5&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/indeed/messaging/postLaunchResearch.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;My contribution:&lt;/strong&gt; Categorized thousands of lines of survey results. Led a brainstorming session with wider team. Worked with design technologist and user researcher to run usertesting studies. Created improvement tickets for developers.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;smll&quot;&gt;Phase 4&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;post-mvp-shapingroadmap&quot;&gt;Post-MVP: Shaping roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the initial mayhem, we fell back into our regular cadence of research and delivery. The foundation was set, we had bandwidth, and were far enough ahead of our engineering roadmap to lift our heads and think about our vision. A few concepts we researched:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;voice-introductions&quot;&gt;Voice introductions&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empowering job seekers to send the first message, while giving employers a more compelling cover letter replacement.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/indeed/messaging/audioIntros.png&quot; alt=&quot;Voice intros&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;framework-for-enriched-messaging&quot;&gt;Framework for ‘enriched messaging’&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hybrid graphical and text conversation interface. Important guidelines for other teams creating messaging plugins.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/indeed/messaging/modules.png&quot; alt=&quot;Enriched messaging&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;template-management--functional-placeholders&quot;&gt;Template management &amp;amp; functional placeholders&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/indeed/messaging/templateMgmt.png&quot; alt=&quot;template management&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We eventually got our ducks in a row, traveled to Austin, Seattle, and San Francisco, and codified our vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;prioritization-grid&quot;&gt;Prioritization grid&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/indeed/messaging/impactGrid.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;template management&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;timeline&quot;&gt;Timeline&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/indeed/messaging/timeline.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;template management&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;company-wide-presentation&quot;&gt;Company-wide presentation&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/indeed/messaging/pres.png&quot; alt=&quot;template management&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Sharing messaging vision and progress with SLT and wider UX org (100+ designers).&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyDiv&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;SVP of Product presents vision in keynote at Indeed Interactive&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Indeed's SVP of Product asked us to produce a demo for his keynote at Indeed Interactive conference in 2019. Here's the result:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/368334454&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        In the end we worked with a design technologist to build this whole flow and they successfully demoed it live!
    &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/09/indeed/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/10/09/indeed/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pyrus</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- ##### Product overview --&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/367562203&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent two years working with doctors in Seattle and Canada to improve MRI/CT imaging. We focused on VR software for perioperative education and AR-based navigation for minimally-invasive procedures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Key contributions&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Created &lt;mark&gt;business plan&lt;/mark&gt; and prototype to secure initial grant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developed model management app in React.js&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Built &lt;mark&gt;VR interface&lt;/mark&gt; in Unity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designed &amp;amp; researched first-of-its-kind VR input model, ‘Touch Motion,’ that combines Oculus Touch and Leap Motion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Created mobile app that used sockets to connect to a HoloLens and function as a input device&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Led frequent &lt;mark&gt;contextual inquiry and usability analyses&lt;/mark&gt; with doctors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyDiv&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h5&gt;Key design challenges&lt;/h5&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Maintaining a user-centered approach in a highly regulated, complex technical environment with a broad constituency&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Discovery &amp;amp; learning: Building relationships with hospitals and practitioners to establish consistent feedback loop&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Control in VR: Identifying ideal input model that's learnable, precise, and natural&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tool selection menu: How do users move between different fuctions in VR?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Model managament: Streamlining the process of importing DICOM images from workstations and getting them into our VR environment&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Pivoting into AR&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;smll&quot;&gt;Challenge 1&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;maintaining-a-user-centered-approach-in-a-highly-regulated-complex-technical-environment-with-a-broad-constituency&quot;&gt;Maintaining a user-centered approach in a highly regulated, complex technical environment with a broad constituency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;solution-1-up-front-due-diligence&quot;&gt;Solution 1: Up-front due diligence&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pyrus/product_plan.png&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstracted product and business planning helped identify tertiary audiences, contextual/regulatory constraints, and aligned all members of the team around key milestones and deliverables. In the face of enigmatic requirements, perpetual famine, and complex healthcare go-to-market, up-front planning helped clarify milestones, recognize wider market trends, and navigate the regulatory labrynth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;solution-problem-mapping&quot;&gt;Solution: Problem mapping&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pyrus/journey_map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Challenge&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Outcome&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Complex service environment&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Clarity and scope of problem&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Diverse constituency&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Understanding of disparate needs and influences&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Many potential use cases&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Artifact for use in interviews&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyDiv&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;smll&quot;&gt;Challenge 2&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt; Discovery &amp;amp; learning: Building relationships with hospitals and practitioners to establish consistent feedback loop&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; controls=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/images/pyrus/research.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/video&gt;

    &lt;h5&gt;Solution: Rolling play-pen&lt;/h5&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    Anyone who's experimented with VR is familiar with the rats nest of sensors and cables. We spent half the week outside of the office (with a scooter as our primary mode of transportation!) and our caravan was branded the &quot;rolling play-pen.&quot; Though we laughed at the time, I now realize it was this tactic that guaranteed our success.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;smll&quot;&gt;Challenge 3&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;control-in-vr-identifying-ideal-input-model-thats-learnable-precise-and-natural&quot;&gt;Control in VR: Identifying ideal input model that’s learnable, precise, and natural&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;mark&gt;biggest design challenge&lt;/mark&gt; was figuring out how to  accomodate ‘natural’ gestures with efficient, precise, and predictable input. Efficiency is critical for doctors and they had a low threshold for onboarding and recall. This was the most important part of our user experience and where we invested the most in research. The following highlights key steps in our investigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;experiment-1-google-cardboard&quot;&gt;Experiment 1: Google Cardboard&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pyrus/exp1_googleCardboard.png&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Benefits&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Drawbacks&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mobile; lightweight &amp;amp; accessible&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Way too limited (just gaze and one button)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Laggy with big models&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;experiment-2-dk2--leap-motion&quot;&gt;Experiment 2: DK2 + Leap Motion&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pyrus/exp2_dk.png&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Benefits&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Drawbacks&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Hardware light (no controller to learn)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Tracking: Unpredictable &amp;amp; imprecise&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Basic controls are intuitive&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;IR silhouette intersection&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;experiment-3-xbox-controller&quot;&gt;Experiment 3: Xbox controller&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pyrus/exp3_xbox.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Benefits&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Drawbacks&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Predictable &amp;amp; Comforable&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Difficult to extract substructures&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Lots of input options&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Doctors hated it; felt like gaming.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;experiment-4-perception-neuron&quot;&gt;Experiment 4: Perception Neuron&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pyrus/exp4_neuron.png&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Benefits&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Drawbacks&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Performant &amp;amp; Precise tracking&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Way too much configuration&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Clunky, fragile hardware&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;experiment-5-touch-motion-️&quot;&gt;Experiment 5: Touch motion ❤️&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; controls=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/images/pyrus/exp5_touchmotion.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;!-- Menus --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyDiv&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;smll&quot;&gt;Challenge 4&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Action menu with touch motion&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Touch motion hit the sweet spot between precision and intuition. Our next challenge was to create an efficient system for switching between modes and tools.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h5&gt;v1: Pane&lt;/h5&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pyrus/touchmotion.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Users summoned a menu with the controller and selected actions with their free hand. This was easy to create using Unity Canvas and Leap Motion button elements, but it wasn't scalable and prone to selection error.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h5&gt;v2: Radial menu&lt;/h5&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pyrus/design_controller.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
      &lt;thead&gt;
          &lt;tr&gt;
              &lt;th&gt;Challenge&lt;/th&gt;
              &lt;th&gt;Outcome&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;/thead&gt;
      &lt;tbody&gt;
          &lt;tr&gt;
              &lt;td&gt;Hiding functionality behind buttons resulted in recall challenge&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;td&gt;Faster and easily memorized menu selection flow&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;/tr&gt;
          &lt;tr&gt;
              &lt;td&gt;Two-handed menus are slow and require dexterity&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;td&gt;Fewer human factors issues&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;/tr&gt;
          &lt;tr&gt;
              &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;td&gt;MORE new user errors&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;/tr&gt;
          
      &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;smll&quot;&gt;Challenge 5&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/09/pyrus/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/10/09/pyrus/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ajua</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ajua is a research technology company out of MIT that connects health researchers and businesses with populations in hard-to-reach areas using SMS. After spending a summer in Nairobi, I continued to provide design and front-end development support during my second year of grad school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The techincal expectations were much greater than anticipated, so I spent the first month focused on research and design, while spending evenings studying front-end languages, frameworks, and best practices. In the second half of my internship I was spending most of my time on interface development and battling d3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ultimately worked on a product called Consumer Wallet that measured Kenya’s cash-based economy in real time that was covered in Forbes, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/montymunford/2017/05/03/msurvey-and-safaricom-continue-kenyas-mobile-money-revolution/#555cc62d133d&quot;&gt;Forbes article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ajua/research.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Placeholder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![Placeholder](/assets/images/placeholder-20.jpg)

Jean shorts pour-over chicharrones woke. Kinfolk next level chia master cleanse. Messenger bag green juice tumeric trust fund pour-over vegan. Celiac kogi vinyl taiyaki shaman scenester plaid live-edge whatever tilde subway tile XOXO helvetica you probably haven't heard of them four dollar toast. Knausgaard franzen mumblecore normcore microdosing. Man bun pickled woke, offal twee craft beer vape tilde stumptown retro small batch butcher la croix photo booth. 

Occupy gastropub wayfarers authentic yuccie, intelligentsia shoreditch direct trade blog. Hell of neutra gochujang knausgaard irony normcore enamel pin. Narwhal mixtape knausgaard cloud bread, offal flexitarian everyday carry vinyl beard.

Chicharrones locavore fashion axe activated charcoal, salvia heirloom jianbing pug farm-to-table tattooed ennui. Wayfarers poke edison bulb banjo street art normcore. Gentrify hashtag health goth listicle biodiesel chambray wolf vape. Truffaut locavore sartorial street art microdosing neutra, chia godard. Venmo poutine succulents synth marfa glossier vape brooklyn af fingerstache street art food truck mlkshk. Twee trust fund etsy bicycle rights umami, brunch ennui mlkshk poutine. Ennui ugh cred distillery. Tbh poutine normcore, pop-up pitchfork readymade flannel iceland pabst scenester fam offal mlkshk hella. 

Hella gastropub dreamcatcher tumblr lumbersexual kinfolk. Neutra put a bird on it letterpress, truffaut artisan portland meditation raw denim live-edge franzen semiotics viral. Neutra selfies knausgaard green juice raclette. Blue bottle disrupt 8-bit coloring book farm-to-table seitan. Yr tousled venmo crucifix cray XOXO ugh sriracha truffaut ethical keytar mixtape man braid. Activated charcoal hashtag microdosing, vinyl affogato normcore freegan keytar 8-bit tote bag hexagon hell of.

![Placeholder](/assets/images/placeholder-23.jpg#full)

Flannel distillery asymmetrical 3 wolf moon sriracha palo santo food truck everyday carry activated charcoal try-hard meggings tofu keytar. Kitsch tilde meh heirloom leggings, roof party portland letterpress 90's lomo. Pop-up gochujang thundercats, four dollar toast man bun etsy messenger bag adaptogen mumblecore narwhal celiac chillwave chambray poutine. Vaporware craft beer occupy tattooed authentic cray. Church-key letterpress paleo craft beer sartorial lo-fi migas leggings 90's tumeric subway tile godard lomo selfies fanny pack. Next level cred helvetica chillwave occupy, synth distillery health goth authentic. 

![Placeholder](/assets/images/placeholder-29.jpg#full)

Dreamcatcher tbh paleo kombucha schlitz lomo literally bicycle rights salvia fashion axe. Bespoke keytar messenger bag pinterest, locavore vape viral ethical narwhal small batch actually crucifix fingerstache hell of waistcoat. 

![Placeholder](/assets/images/placeholder-2.jpg)

Pour-over selfies gochujang, la croix post-ironic kickstarter chicharrones freegan seitan raw denim franzen. Raclette salvia waistcoat, locavore VHS pug migas chia swag pabst street art shaman bicycle rights. Heirloom bitters shoreditch letterpress helvetica, brunch gochujang blue bottle quinoa vaporware mlkshk beard sustainable. Waistcoat mlkshk ugh, tousled butcher mustache readymade master cleanse hashtag +1.

Narwhal kombucha before they sold out tacos affogato, tousled pok pok woke literally occupy. Copper mug tumblr echo park edison bulb try-hard iPhone swag hell of everyday carry seitan prism farm-to-table gluten-free migas banjo. Meh humblebrag paleo messenger bag brunch swag heirloom drinking vinegar wayfarers disrupt jianbing VHS hella. Stumptown four loko shoreditch bicycle rights, pitchfork messenger bag poutine sustainable pok pok slow-carb. Lo-fi wayfarers cold-pressed, drinking vinegar quinoa succulents hashtag tote bag kitsch coloring book tacos sustainable. Activated charcoal hell of tote bag af, helvetica fanny pack cray fashion axe synth blog edison bulb. Subway tile iceland banh mi pickled air plant. Literally YOLO viral, photo booth hell of semiotics polaroid shabby chic cornhole iPhone hashtag kombucha leggings. Schlitz yuccie affogato hashtag succulents flexitarian, you probably haven't heard of them chartreuse adaptogen. Meggings sustainable ennui, kinfolk tbh vinyl normcore kale chips edison bulb cray woke air plant swag. Neutra cardigan palo santo whatever. --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/09/msurvey/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/10/09/msurvey/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
